Josh Dixon

(236) 889-6605 | Vancouver, BC

<u>LinkedIn</u> | joshdixon1995@hotmail.co.uk

OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

A Front End Developer with 1.5 years of experience working in an agile environment developing, testing and peer reviewing code that reaches hundreds of thousands of users. Experienced in JavaScript, React, NextJs and PHP. Authorized to work for any Canadian company for two years without LMIA.

WORK EXPERIENCE

The Collecting Group Ltd

Nottingham, UK

Website Developer

September 2021 - April 2023

Designed, developed and maintained features for two online auction websites (collectingcars.com and watchcollecting.com).

- Tripled the selection of languages available and added translation support due to rapid growth internationally. Also revamped the UX and UI of the language selection React component.
- Optimized development and deployment of static pages by implementing Contentful CMS. This resulted in faster turnaround times for policy page changes, addition of news articles and the ability to deploy static pages independently without requiring developer input.
- Developed microservice for handling user data and displaying badges alongside usernames. Improving trust between reputable buyers and sellers on our platform.
- Conducted an SEO audit and improved page load time and Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) score, resulting in better search engine visibility and user experience.
- Designed and developed a 'press cuttings' page in response to a business request. The feature allows the web-ops team to input article links in our CMS, which are then rendered as article cards on the webpage using metadata from the provided link.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to build and test a new responsive navigation system for both brands.

Nottingham Forest FC Ltd

Nottingham, UK

Team Photographer

September 2021 - April 2023

- Shoot, edit and caption imagery of matchday events, game action and press conferences.
- Oversaw the organization and maintenance of the club's image archive.
- Provide imagery for corporate partners and sponsors, including imagery of advertising materials, shirt sponsors and stadium branding.
- Produce all content in line with the club's digital strategy and style.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, NextJs, Jest, Cypress, JQuery, XSLT, ChakraUI, Framer Motion Tools: Git, GitHub, CircleCl, PHPStorm, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Contentful, Postman, Hotjar

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials | Amazon Web Services Training **UX and Accessible Design** | UAL Creative Computing Institute

EDUCATION

Worksop College Worksop, UK 2011 - 2013 A Levels in Applied Business, Design & Technology and Physical Education

The Grove Secondary School

Balderton, UK

6 GCSE's grade A-C including Mathematics and English

2006 - 2011